<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Lagos Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="about_lag">
        Lagos (/ˈlɑːɡoʊs/ /ˈleɪɡɒs/ lay-gos), is the most populous city in Nigeria,
        the second fastest-growing city in Africa and the seventh in the world. The population
        of Lagos according to the Lagos State Government was 17.5 million, a number disputed by the
        Nigerian Government and judged unreliable by the National Population Commission of Nigeria.
        The latest reports estimate the population at 21 million, making Lagos the largest city in
        Africa.\n\n
        Lagos is a port which originated on islands separated by creeks, such as Lagos Island,
        fringing the southwest mouth of Lagos Lagoon while protected from the Atlantic Ocean by
        barrier islands and long sand spits such as Bar Beach, which stretch up to 100
        kilometres (62 miles) east and west of the mouth.
        \n\n


        Portuguese explorer Rui de Sequeira visited the area in 1472, naming the area around the city Lago
        de Curamo; indeed the present name is Portuguese for “lakes”. Another explanation is that
        Lagos was named for Lagos, Portugal—a maritime town which, at the time, was the main centre
        of Portuguese expeditions down the African coast, and whose own name is derived from the
        Latin word Lacobriga.\n\n



    </string>

    <string name="eko_language">
        Although English is the Nigeria Official Language, almost 75 percent of the entire population
        in Lagos speak and understand English or <b>pidgin English</b>. Majority speak Yoruba, almost 70 percent
        speak or understand Yoruba Language. Around 30 percent can speak or understand Igbo Language.
        Around 7 percent speak Hausa Language.
    </string>

    <string name="history">

        Lagos was originally inhabited by the Awori subgroup of the Yoruba people. Under the
        leadership of the Oloye Olofin, the Awori moved to an island now called Iddo and then to
        the larger Lagos Island. In the 15th century, the Awori settlement was conquered by the
        Benin Empire and the island became a Benin war-camp called “Eko” under Oba Orhogba, the
        Oba of Benin at the time. The Yoruba still use the name Eko to refer to Lagos.\n\n
Lagos, which means “lakes”, was a name given to the settlement by the Portuguese. The present-day
        Lagos state has a high percentage of Awori, who migrated to the area from Isheri along the
        Ogun river. Throughout history, it was home to a number of warring ethnic groups who had
        settled in the area. Following its early settlement by the Awori nobility, and its conquest
        by the Bini warlords of Benin, the state first came to the attention of the Portuguese in
        the 15th century.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="geography">
        Most of the population lives on the mainland, and most industries are located there too.
        Lagos is known for its music and night life, which used to be located in areas around Yaba
        and Surulere. In recent years more night clubs have sprung up on the island, making the
        island, particularly Victoria Island, the main nightlife attraction. These islands are
        separated from the mainland by the main channel draining the lagoon into the Atlantic Ocean,
        which forms Lagos Harbour. The islands are separated from each other by creeks of varying
        sizes and are connected to Lagos Island by bridges. The smaller sections of some creeks
        have been sand filled and built over.Lagos Mainland districts include Ebute-Meta, Surulere,
        Yaba (location of the University of Lagos) and Ikeja, site of Murtala Muhammed
        International Airport and capital of Lagos State.

    </string>

    <string name="climate">
        In the Köppen climate classification system, Lagos has a tropical wet and dry climate
        (Aw) that borders on a tropical monsoon climate (Am). Lagos experiences two rainy seasons,
        with the heaviest rains falling from April to July and a weaker rainy season in October and
        November. There is a brief relatively dry spell in August and September and a longer dry
        season from December to March.

        Monthly rainfall between May and July averages over 400 mm (16 in), while in August and
        September it is down to 200 mm (7.9 in) and in December as low as 25 mm (0.98 in). The main
        dry season is accompanied by harmattan winds from the Sahara Desert, which between December
        and early February can be quite strong. The highest maximum temperature ever recorded in
        Lagos was 37.3 °C (99.1 °F) and the minimum 13.9 °C (57.0 °F).
    </string>

    <string name="brt_buses">
        BRT is a transport option, which relies on the use of dedicated interference free segregated
        lanes to guarantee fast and reliable bus travel. It is a high performance public transport
        bus service which aims to combine bus lanes with high-quality bus stations, vehicles,
        amenities and branding to achieve the performance and quality of a light rail or metro
        system, with the flexibility, cost and simplicity of a bus system. The BRT buses run on
        physically segregated lanes and thus make them faster in a situation where there is traffic
        congestion. It is one of the several options available for tackling the huge public
        transport predicaments of Lagos.
        \n\n
        <b>PRICING AND ROUTES</b>\n\n
        <b>Routes: </b>Ikorodu- Mile 12- Ikeja – Maryland – Yaba – Surulere – Apapa – CMS – TBS
\n\n
        <b>Passenger Capacity/Bus: </b>80 (37 sitting/43 standing)\n\n
        <b>Pricing: </b>Price ranges from 70 Naira to 300 Naira depending on where you are heading to.
    </string>

    <string name="ferry">
        The Lagos State Ferry Services Corporation (LSFSC) or Lagos Ferry Services Company
        (also known as LAGFERRY) is the major ferry services provider in Lagos State. Although
        Lagos ferry services commenced operations in 1925, passenger ferries gradually
        intensified until the 1970s which led to the establishment of Lagferry in
        1983. Lagferry works in conjunction with Lagos State Waterways Authority (LASWA), National
        Inland Waterways Authority (NIWA) and Nigeria Maritime Administration and Safety Agency
        (NIMASA). Besides Lagferry, other private ferry operators also use modern ferry boats to
        provide commercial transport services between Ikorodu, Lagos Island, Apapa and Victoria
        Island.
    </string>

    <string name="banks">
        Nigeria\'s currency is the Nigerian Naira (NGN), which is divided into 100 kobo.
        The naira is available in the following denominations:\n\n
        <b>Notes:</b> 1,000 NGN, 500 NGN, 200 NGN, 100 NGN, 50 NGN, 20 NGN, 10 NGN and 5 NGN.\n\n
        <b>Coins:</b> 1 NGN, 2 NGN and 50 kobo.
    </string>

    <string name="banking">
        The Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) is the main bank in Nigeria and the institution that
        regulates banking in the country. Other banks in Nigeria include, amongst others, Ecobank
        Nigeria, Access Bank, Citibank, Standard Chartered Bank and Union Bank of Nigeria.\n\n
        Banking systems in Nigeria, such as Internet banking, do exist and offer standard services,
        but are often down, and during these times only one’s bank balance will be available.
        Not to mention, personal information is not guaranteed to be safe, and the perception is
        that the system itself is pretty unreliable and way behind the times.
    </string>

    <string name="atm">
ATMs are available at some banks, but not all of them accept foreign cards. Most ATMs have a daily
        withdrawal limit of around 150,000 NGN. ATM fraud is prevalent in Nigeria, so vigilance and
        communication with the bank will be essential.\n\n

<b>Credit cards</b>\n
Nigeria is largely a cash-based society, so cash will still be necessary for many purchases.
        More establishments are starting to accept debit/credit cards as standard forms of payment
        for goods and services, but be sure to be extra wary when paying with a card, as fraud is a
        major concern.\n\n
        If using a credit card for any transactions, expats should carefully look at their bank statements
        to ensure there has not been any credit card fraud. Expats should notify their bank before
        moving to Nigeria and using their card, as many banks will automatically cancel a card after
        just one Nigerian transaction.
    </string>

    <string name="operational_structure">
        The Service has three (3) Directorates, Eight Zonal offices, Thirty-Six State Commands and
        Federal Capital Territory and Immigration offices in the 774 local government areas.\n\n
        <b>The three Directorates are:</b>\n\n
        <b>Finance, Administration and Technical Services(FATS)</b>\n\n
        The FATS directorate is statutorily charged with the responsibility of policy initiation,
        formulation, articulation and implementation. It is equally responsible for the financial
        management, recruitment, discipline, postings, deployments and promotion of officers and
        men of the Service. Operations, Passport, Border Patrol, ECOWAS and African Affairs It is
        responsible for the provision of various immigration facilities such as:\n\n
        Visa\n
        CERPAC\n
        Passports\n\n
        <b>Investigation, Inspectorate and Enforcement</b>\n\n
        <b>Investigation and Aliens Control</b>
    </string>

    <string name="visa">
        <b>Who qualifies</b> \n
        - Persons wishing to visit Nigeria for the purpose of tourism\n
        - Individuals who want to visit family members\n \n
        <b>Requirements for the issuance of Tourist Visa / Entry Permit</b>\n\n
        Valid passport with minimum of 6 months validity\n
        Valid Visa to onward destination\n
        Valid Airline return ticket\n
        Evidence of funds\n
        Evidence of Hotel reservation\n
        Acceptance of IR (Immigration Responsibility)\n
        Validity\n
        - Not valid for employment
    </string>

    <string name="emergency">
        In case of emergrncy of any sort, just call any of these numbers:\n\n
        <b>Toll free Emergency dial</b> - 767 / 112 (Police, Ambulance, Emergencies etc)\n\n
        <b>Fire Service</b> - 01 6584712, 7280500, 7280501, 7280502, 7280503\n\n
        <b>LASAMBUS</b> - 01 6584713\n\n
        <b>LASTMA</b> - 01 6584715\n\n
        <b>KAI</b> - 01 6583684\n\n
        <b>LASEMA</b> - 01 4187160, 4187161, 4187162\n\n
        <b>Women Abuse Domestic Violence Helpline</b> - 01 7617508, 08085754226, 08102678443\n\n
        <b>Child Abuse Helpline</b> - 08085753932, 08102678442 07098733732,
        Email: protectachild@yahoo.com, protectachild@gmail.com\n\n
        <b>AA Rescue (Vehicle Breakdown Assistance)</b> - 4614999, 08025551111/3333, 08035612222\n\n
        <b>Flying Doctors (Air ambulances and medical crews)</b> - 0706 920 1299\n

    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_attraction">Attraction</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="events">Events</string>
    <string name="club">Night Clubs</string>
    <string name="historical">Others</string>


</resources>
