<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Lagos Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="about_lag">
        Lagos (/ˈlɑːɡoʊs/ /ˈleɪɡɒs/ lay-gos), is the most populous city in Nigeria,
        the second fastest-growing city in Africa and the seventh in the world. The population
        of Lagos according to the Lagos State Government was 17.5 million, a number disputed by the
        Nigerian Government and judged unreliable by the National Population Commission of Nigeria.
        The latest reports estimate the population at 21 million, making Lagos the largest city in
        Africa.\n\n
        Lagos is a port which originated on islands separated by creeks, such as Lagos Island,
        fringing the southwest mouth of Lagos Lagoon while protected from the Atlantic Ocean by
        barrier islands and long sand spits such as Bar Beach, which stretch up to 100
        kilometres (62 miles) east and west of the mouth.
        \n\n


Portuguese explorer Rui de Sequeira visited the area in 1472, naming the area around the city Lago
        de Curamo; indeed the present name is Portuguese for “lakes”. Another explanation is that
        Lagos was named for Lagos, Portugal—a maritime town which, at the time, was the main centre
        of Portuguese expeditions down the African coast, and whose own name is derived from the
        Latin word Lacobriga.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="history">

        Lagos was originally inhabited by the Awori subgroup of the Yoruba people. Under the
        leadership of the Oloye Olofin, the Awori moved to an island now called Iddo and then to
        the larger Lagos Island. In the 15th century, the Awori settlement was conquered by the
        Benin Empire and the island became a Benin war-camp called “Eko” under Oba Orhogba, the
        Oba of Benin at the time. The Yoruba still use the name Eko to refer to Lagos.\n\n
Lagos, which means “lakes”, was a name given to the settlement by the Portuguese. The present-day
        Lagos state has a high percentage of Awori, who migrated to the area from Isheri along the
        Ogun river. Throughout history, it was home to a number of warring ethnic groups who had
        settled in the area. Following its early settlement by the Awori nobility, and its conquest
        by the Bini warlords of Benin, the state first came to the attention of the Portuguese in
        the 15th century.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="geography">
        Most of the population lives on the mainland, and most industries are located there too.
        Lagos is known for its music and night life, which used to be located in areas around Yaba
        and Surulere. In recent years more night clubs have sprung up on the island, making the
        island, particularly Victoria Island, the main nightlife attraction. These islands are
        separated from the mainland by the main channel draining the lagoon into the Atlantic Ocean,
        which forms Lagos Harbour. The islands are separated from each other by creeks of varying
        sizes and are connected to Lagos Island by bridges. The smaller sections of some creeks
        have been sand filled and built over.Lagos Mainland districts include Ebute-Meta, Surulere,
        Yaba (location of the University of Lagos) and Ikeja, site of Murtala Muhammed
        International Airport and capital of Lagos State.

    </string>

    <string name="climate">
        In the Köppen climate classification system, Lagos has a tropical wet and dry climate
        (Aw) that borders on a tropical monsoon climate (Am). Lagos experiences two rainy seasons,
        with the heaviest rains falling from April to July and a weaker rainy season in October and
        November. There is a brief relatively dry spell in August and September and a longer dry
        season from December to March.

        Monthly rainfall between May and July averages over 400 mm (16 in), while in August and
        September it is down to 200 mm (7.9 in) and in December as low as 25 mm (0.98 in). The main
        dry season is accompanied by harmattan winds from the Sahara Desert, which between December
        and early February can be quite strong. The highest maximum temperature ever recorded in
        Lagos was 37.3 °C (99.1 °F) and the minimum 13.9 °C (57.0 °F).
    </string>

</resources>
